<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
      xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Akeeba Kickstart 3.0 User's Guide</title>

    <author>
      <personname><firstname>Nicholas</firstname><othername>K.</othername><surname>Dionysopoulos</surname></personname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname>AkeebaBackup.com</orgname>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <pubdate>December 2013</pubdate>

    <copyright>
      <year>2013</year>

      <holder>Akeeba Ltd</holder>
    </copyright>

    <legalnotice>
      <para>Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
      document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version
      1.3 or any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with
      no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts. A
      copy of the license is included in the appendix entitled "The GNU Free
      Documentation License".</para>
    </legalnotice>

    <abstract>
      <para>This book covers the use of the <application>Akeeba
      </application>Kickstart web-based archive extraction software. It
      includes reference for its interface, as well as instructions for
      automating its operation.</para>
    </abstract>
  </info>

  <chapter xml:id="introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <section xml:id="overview">
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para><application>Kickstart</application> is a <acronym>PHP</acronym>
      executable file ( <emphasis>script</emphasis> ) use to automate the
      steps required before and after the restoration of site backed up with
      <application>Akeeba Backup</application> in a great extent. It can be
      used as a simple and efficient method of extracting the
      <application>Akeeba Backup</application> archives directly on the target
      server, or even used to extract other archive files including CMS and
      script installation files (e.g. <trademark>Joomla!</trademark>,
      WordPress, Drupal, phpBB), update packages (Joomla! and WordPress can
      especially benefit from this use) or even archives containing large
      amounts of files you need to get on your server, fast.</para>

      <para>When used with backup archives,
      <application>Kickstart</application> streamlines the archive extraction
      - uploading - restoration - post-restoration workflow by allowing you to
      omit unnecessary steps. As a matter of fact, you only need to upload
      Kickstart and the backup archive on the server you want to restore your
      site to. Kickstart will extract (i.e. "unzip") the archive
      <emphasis>right on the server</emphasis> , rename your
      <filename>.htaccess</filename> and php.ini files and give you a button
      to start the restoration script included in the backup archive (for
      example, <application>Akeeba Backup</application> Installer). When
      you're done with the restoration script, you click on the new button
      appearing on the Kickstart interface and it will rename back your
      <filename>.htaccess</filename> and php.ini files, remove the
      installation directory, delete the backup archive and finally remove
      itself as well. Housekeeping is taken care of itself!</para>

      <para>Kickstart is also localisable, meaning that it can display itself
      in your own language. All you have to do is to upload your language's
      translation INI file in the same directory as
      <filename>kickstart.php</filename> .</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="why-we-need-kickstart">
      <title>Why do we need Kickstart, anyway?</title>

      <para>Even though Akeeba Backup is designed as an effortless way of
      backing up your site, it is only good up to the point of having a backup
      archive. Restoring it is a pretty much different story.</para>

      <para>At first, you have to download the file to your PC. Then extract
      it. Then upload all the files, via FTP, to you site (and, man, this is
      slow or what?). Then rename <filename>.htaccess</filename> to
      <filename>htaccess.txt</filename> and <filename>php.ini</filename> to
      <filename>php.ini.bak</filename> in order to avoid any conflicts. Go
      through the restoration process, which is the easy part. Then remove the
      installation directory. Finally, rename
      <filename>htaccess.txt</filename> to <filename>.htaccess</filename> and
      <filename>php.ini.bak</filename> to <filename>php.ini</filename>.</para>

      <para>Did you notice something? Most of this is a common predefined
      procedure. The only human intervention truly required is for the
      restoration process part. Moreover, FTP'ing all those 3000+ files of
      even the smallest full site backup is an overkill. Because of all of
      this, Kickstart was born.</para>

      <para>Kickstart works in conjunction with the ZIP / JPA archives,
      directly on the target server. Nothing else is required. You just upload
      kickstart.php and your archive to the server, visit
      <uri>http://www.yourdomain.com/kickstart.php</uri>, select the archive,
      wait, go through the restoration process, click the cleanup button and
      presto! Your site is up and running; the kickstart.php, the backup
      archive and the installation folder all gone, automatically. Even the
      <filename>.htaccess</filename> and <filename>php.ini</filename> renaming
      took care of itself. Isn't this too good to be true?</para>

      <para>Well, almost. You actually need to either turn off PHP Safe Mode,
      or make sure the target folder is owned by the same user as the one your
      web server runs on: this is a PHP limitation we can't overcome.
      Alternatively, you can supply FTP connection information and Kickstart
      will use the - much slower - FTP mode to write the extracted files to
      your site.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="what-kickstart-is-and-what-it-is-not">
      <title>What Kickstart is and what it's not</title>

      <para>Kickstart is an interactive archive extraction script and a
      clean-up tool. Counter-intuitively, it is <emphasis>not</emphasis> a
      site restoration utility per se. Kickstart performs the steps required
      before and after site restoration, whereas the site restoration
      procedure itself is carried out by the installer script which was
      included in your backup archive at backup time. To make it crystal
      clear, here is the flow of a Kickstart-powered site restoration
      procedure:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Uploading files. This is done manually. You upload
          <filename>kickstart.php</filename> and the backup archive (ZIP or
          JPA format) to the intended site's root.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Archive extraction</emphasis> . This is
          done by Kickstart. The backup archive is extracted. At this point
          your site is not yet ready to work.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Restoration process. This is done by installer which was
          included in the archive and now extracted on your server. You are
          asked some questions, the database dump data is restored to the new
          database and the new CMS configuration file is written on the disk.
          At this point, your site may or not be ready to work, depending on
          the reliance upon a <filename>.htaccess</filename> file.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Restoration of
          <filename>.htaccess</filename> </emphasis>and
          <filename>php.ini</filename> . This is done by Kickstart. The
          automatically renamed copies of your original
          <filename>.htaccess</filename> and <filename>php.ini</filename>
          files are renamed back to their proper names to allow correct site
          operation.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis role="bold">Cleanup of unnecessary files</emphasis>.
          This is done by Kickstart. The backup archive, the installation
          directory and <filename>kickstart.php</filename> are no longer
          needed and therefore deleted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>As you can see, Kickstart is a very generic tool, not strictly
      limited to restoring Akeeba Backup backup archives. As a matter of fact,
      we have used it to easily upgrade our sites to newer CMS versions
      without the hassle of uploading tons of PHP files!</para>

      <tip>
        <para>The correct way to see Kickstart is as a generic, interactive,
        web-based archive extraction script which can also clean up after
        itself.</para>
      </tip>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="about-the-name">
      <title>About the name</title>

      <para>The naming of this script is a small tribute to one of the first
      computing platforms I came to know: the Amiga 500. The initial boot
      loader, pretty much responsible for initializing the operating system's
      boot process was called Kickstart. This script has an analogous function
      in the restoration process of Akeeba Backup-generated backup archives:
      it takes care of everything up to the point the actual restoration
      process starts.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="before-using">
    <title>Before using Kickstart</title>

    <section xml:id="getting-kickstart">
      <title>Getting Kickstart</title>

      <para>Kickstart is part of the Akeeba Backup release system. As such, it
      can be downloaded from our site, <uri
      xlink:href="http://www.akeebabackup.com">http://www.akeebabackup.com</uri>.
      All packages are named
      <filename>kickstart-<replaceable>VERSION</replaceable>.zip</filename>,
      where VERSION is the version number. Each package contains kickstart.php
      itself, as well as all the available translation files. You have to
      extract this archive and upload kickstart.php and any translation INI
      files you may need to your site.</para>

      <para>The latest Kickstart version can be always retrieved by visiting
      <link
      xlink:href="http://www.akeebabackup.com/latest">http://www.akeebabackup.com/latest</link>.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="requirements">
      <title>Requirements</title>

      <para>Kickstart is a PHP 5 application. It will not work with PHP 4. The
      full list or required server configuration is:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><trademark>Joomla!</trademark> and PHP version compatibilities
          are detailed in <link
          xlink:href="https://www.akeebabackup.com/compatibility.html">our
          Version Compatibility matrix</link>.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>PHP mod_zlib available. This is available by default.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>PHP Safe Mode disabled, or correct directory ownerships, or
          FTP connection parameters must be entered</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The last requirement must be further explained. PHP with Safe Mode
      enabled will refuse to create folders inside another folder which is not
      owned by the same user as the one the web server (Apache) runs under,
      even if the folder is otherwise writable. Kickstart will fail in this
      case. Alternatively, if you supply the FTP connection information,
      Kickstart will try to use FTP to connect to your site and write the
      extracted files.</para>

      <important>
        <para>If you use the FTP mode, Kickstart will require the specified
        temporary directory to be directly writable by PHP (usually, 0777
        permissions help) or it will attempt to create a temporary directory
        of its own. If this procedure fails, Kickstart will notify you that
        the temporary directory is not writable.</para>
      </important>

      <para>Moreover, if you already have a site installed on the target
      server you have to ensure that all folders and files are writable. If
      not, Kickstart will fail and leave your site in a possibly broken
      state.</para>

      <para>Finally, if your server doesn't support base64 decoding (e.g. the
      base64_decode function is disabled) you need an Internet connection.
      Normally, the required jQuery library is fetched from a base64 encoded
      resource inside the kickstart.php file. If the decoding is not possible,
      Kickstart will fall back to loading it from Google's AJAX API Library
      CDN, which requires an Internet connection and access to Google's CDN
      not be restricted by your firewall or Internet security suite.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="using-kickstart">
    <title>Using Kickstart</title>

    <section xml:id="preparing-for-the-extraction">
      <title>Preparing for the extraction</title>

      <para>The first step is to download the latest release of Kickstart. It
      can be always retrieved by visiting <link
      xlink:href="http://www.akeebabackup.com/latest">http://www.akeebabackup.com/latest</link>.
      It comes as a ZIP package. <emphasis>Do not</emphasis> try to install it
      in Joomla!. Instead, you'll have to unzip it first. The extracted files
      are <filename>kickstart.php</filename> and a series of .ini, .js and
      .pem files. The <filename>kickstart.php</filename> file is required for
      Kickstart's operation and self-contained, i.e. it doesn't need any other
      files (or Joomla!) to be installed on your server. The INI files are
      translation files. You only need them if you want Kickstart to appear
      localized in your language. You can safely delete any INI files which
      represent languages you do not understand. The JS files are not
      required, unless you don't have an Internet connection (e.g. restoring
      to a local server without an Internet connection) or have trouble
      accessing the sites where copies of these files are stored in. The
      <filename>cacert.pem</filename> file is required on some servers if you
      are trying to connect to Amazon S3 to download backup archives and might
      be necessary if importing from a URL. If unsure, upload all files (see
      below).</para>

      <para>The second step is uploading those files to your server. Upload
      <filename>kickstart.php</filename> and any files you may need to the
      server path you want the restored site to be installed. If you want the
      site to be extracted to your domain's root (something like
      <uri>http://www.example.com</uri>) you'll have to locate your web root.
      On most servers it appears as a directory named
      <filename>public_html</filename>, <filename>httpdocs</filename>,
      <filename>htdocs</filename>, <filename>www</filename> or something
      similar when you connect to your account by FTP. If unsure, ask your
      host. They know which directory it is without having to guess.</para>

      <para>The third step is getting your archive file to the server. This
      can be currently performed only by having you manually upload the
      archive by FTP to the same directory as the one
      <filename>kickstart.php</filename> is in.</para>

      <para>Two words of caution:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always, no matter what, use the Binary transfer mode to upload
          your backup archives by FTP. If you are using FileZilla you can do
          so by clicking on the Transfer menu, then the Transfer Type submenu
          and making sure that Binary is selected. If you do not do that, most
          FTP software will fall back to ASCII file transfers which will
          corrupt the backup archive and cause extraction issues.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>If you had created a multi-part archive you have to transfer
          all files. In the case of a JPA file they have the same name and
          extensions of .jpa, .j01, .j02 etc. In the case of a ZIP file they
          have the same name and extensions of .zip, .z01, .z02 etc. If any of
          the parts is missing, an extraction error will occur.</para>

          <para>Do note that the installer is included in the beginning of the
          archive. Even in the event of a partial restoration you will most
          likely be able to start the restoration procedure but your site
          <emphasis>will not work properly</emphasis> as many crucial files
          will be missing!</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>When you are done, you can launch Kickstart by visiting its URL.
      It usually has the form of
      <uri>http://www.example.com/kickstart.php</uri>.</para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="kickstart-interface">
      <title>Kickstart's interface</title>

      <section xml:id="initial-dialogue">
        <title>Initial dialogue</title>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>The initial dialogue</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.01.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>Once you launch Kickstart, you'll first get a standard notice
        regarding the top things that you should be aware about:</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Kickstart is not an installer. It is an archive extraction
            tool. The actual installer was put inside the archive file at
            backup time.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Kickstart is not the only way to extract the backup archive.
            You can use Akeeba eXtract Wizard and upload the extracted files
            using FTP instead.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Kickstart is bound by your server's configuration. As such,
            it may not work at all.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>You should download and upload your archive files using FTP
            in Binary transfer mode. Any other method could lead to a corrupt
            backup archive and restoration failure.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Post-restoration site load errors are usually caused by
            .htaccess or php.ini directives. You should understand that blank
            pages, 404 and 500 errors can usually be worked around by editing
            the aforementioned files. It is not our job to mess with your
            configuration files, because this could be dangerous for your
            site.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Kickstart overwrites files without a warning. If you are not
            sure that you are OK with that do not continue.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Trying to restore to the temporary URL of a cPanel host
            (e.g. http://1.2.3.4/~username) will lead to restoration failure
            and your site will appear to be not working. This is normal and
            it's just how your server and CMS software work.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>You are supposed to read the documentation before using this
            software. Most issues can be avoided, or easily worked around, by
            understanding how this software works.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>This text does not imply that there is a problem detected.
            It is standard text displayed every time you launch
            Kickstart.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>Once you have read all of the above and you feel comfortable
        with this information, please press the ESC key to close this dialog
        box.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="the-setup-page">
        <title>The setup page</title>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>The setup page</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.02.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>The setup page contains of four steps.</para>

        <para>The first step is selecting a backup archive. Kickstart
        automatically scans the directory it's in for JPA and ZIP archives,
        populating the drop-down list with these results. If there are
        multiple archives present, please click on the drop down list and
        select the one you would like to use.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>If you are an AKEEBAPRO or AKEEBADELUXE subscriber you can
          download and use the Akeeba Kickstart Professional version. This
          version allows you to fetch archives stored in remote storage. For
          more information, please consult the <link
          linkend="profeatures">Professional Features</link> page of this
          documentation guide.</para>
        </tip>

        <para>The second step is the selection of the extraction method. There
        are two supported methods:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Directly</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>With this method, Kickstart will try to write directly to
              files. This is the ideal method if your server is using suPHP or
              if you have no Joomla! site installed yet. Since Kickstart runs
              in PHP, which in turn might run with your web server's
              privileges, you have to ensure that there are adequate
              permissions to write to the directory Kickstart is in and any
              existing files and directories with the same name as files and
              directories in the archive. If you are not sure, first try to
              remove everything except <filename>kickstart.php</filename> and
              the backup archive from your server. If you still get errors
              regarding the inability to write to files, you'll have to use
              the FTP mode.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use FTP</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>In this mode, Kickstart tries to extract the files in a
              temporary directory, then use FTP to "upload" them to their
              final location. The ability to run Kickstart in this mode
              depends on your server setup. For example, some servers have a
              very strange firewall setup which doesn't allow Kickstart to
              connect to your site's FTP. Also note that Kickstart support FTP
              and FTPS (FTP over implicit SSL). It does not support the SFTP
              protocol, widely known as Secure FTP or FTP over SSH, as it is
              an entirely different protocol with very poor PHP support on
              commercial hosts.</para>

              <para>The only implication in using the FTP mode is that you
              need a writable temporary directory. More on that later.</para>

              <para>When you choose this option, a list of several options
              will expand underneath it. You have to fill them in for
              Kickstart to be able to work.</para>

              <important>
                <para>Kickstart 3.1 or later, when extracting any ZIP archive
                or JPA archives created by Akeeba Backup 3.1 (or later), will
                also try to restore the last file modification time to match
                that of the source server. If you activate the FTP mode this
                will not be possible, as FTP does not support "touching"
                (changing the modification date and time) of files.</para>
              </important>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Hybrid</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This mode combines the previous two in an intelligent
              manner. When selected, Kickstart will first attempt to write to
              the files directly. If this is not possible, i.e. due to
              permissions or ownership of the file or folder being exracted,
              it will automatically make use of the FTP mode to overcome the
              permissions / ownership problem. It effectively works around a
              situation commonly called "permissions hell", where different
              files and folders are owned by different users, making it
              extremely difficult to overwrite them. This is a situation which
              happens very commonly on shared hosting. Therefore <emphasis
              role="bold">we strongly advise clients on shared hosting
              environments to use the Hybrid option</emphasis>.</para>

              <para>The same notes regarding a temporary directory etc as the
              "Use FTP" mode apply for the Hybrid mode as well.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <para>Moreover, there is also the <guilabel>Ignore most
        errors</guilabel> checkbox. When it's checked, Kickstart will not
        throw an error when a file is not writeable. This is useful when you
        are restoring a backup taken on a Linux server to a Windows server. In
        that case, some filenames may contain characters which are valid in
        Linux (e.g. colons) but not on Windows. Checking that option will tell
        Kickstart to ignore file creation errors.</para>

        <warning>
          <para>When that option is enabled, Kickstart will not warn you even
          if a file could not be overwritten because, for example, its
          permissions made it unwriteable. Use with extreme caution and always
          check that all of your files have been extracted properly.</para>
        </warning>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>The FTP Options</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.07.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>The FTP options which get to be displayed, should you choose the
        FTP mode, are:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>FTP Host Name</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If you are using the FTP mode, this defines the address of
              the FTP server used for uploading the files. Do note that you
              must enter only the domain or IP address, without the protocol.
              This means that <uri>ftp.example.com</uri> is correct usage,
              while <uri>ftp://ftp.example.com</uri> is
              <emphasis>incorrect</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>FTP Port</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The TCP/IP port of the FTP server to use. Normally you
              want to use port 21 (default plain FTP port). Only use something
              different if your host tells you so, or if you are using FTPS
              (FTP over SSL).</para>

              <warning>
                <para>If your host tells you to use port 22, their connection
                mode is not compatible with Kickstart. Port 22 is used by the
                SFTP protocol, which is entirely different that the supported
                FTP and FTPS protocols. In this case you have to ask your host
                for plain FTP access to your site.</para>
              </warning>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use FTP over SSL (FTPS)</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Check the box if you want to use the FTPS (FTP over SSL)
              protocol. The default is unchecked which means that Kickstart
              will use an unencrypted connection. Do note that Kickstart
              <emphasis>does not support</emphasis> SFTP, as it is an entirely
              different protocol than FTPS. The names look alike, but the
              protocols have nothing to do with each other.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use FTP Passive Mode</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Check the box to use the FTP Passive mode (default), or
              uncheck it to use the FTP Active mode. Most probably you want to
              use the default value (checked), as it is the only way to work
              around the firewall of your host. A very small minority of hosts
              require the Active mode, but they will tell you so in their FTP
              connection instructions.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>FTP User Name</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The FTP username.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>FTP Password</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The FTP password.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>FTP Directory</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The <emphasis>absolute FTP path</emphasis> to your
              restored site's root. <emphasis role="bold">THIS IS NOT THE SAME
              AS THE FILE SYSTEM PATH TO YOUR SITE'S ROOT!!!</emphasis> The
              easiest way to figure this out is to use FileZilla. Connect to
              your target FTP server with FileZilla. Navigate to the web
              server's root (usually it's a subdirectory named httpdocs,
              htdocs, public_html, http_docs or www). Above the right-hand
              folder pane you will see a text box with a path. Copy this path
              and paste it to this setting.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Temporary Directory</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>As PHP can't directly upload files while they are being
              extracted, Kickstart is extracting them to a temporary directory
              using direct file writes first, then uploads them to their final
              destination using FTP. Normally, Kickstart will try using the
              directory it's stored in to extract the temporary files. Many
              web hosts configure their servers in such a way that this is not
              possible. Using this option you can customise the location of
              the temporary directory to somewhere with adequate permissions.
              You can use either an absolute or a relative (to Kickstart's
              directory) path for this setting.</para>

              <para>If unsure, you can follow an easy workaround. Create a
              directory named <filename>kicktemp</filename> in your site's
              root using FTP and give it 0777 permissions (or world-write
              privileges, e.g. full control to the Everybody pseudo-user, if
              you are using a Windows server). Then type in
              <filename>kicktemp</filename> as this option.</para>

              <tip>
                <para>If you leave this field empty Kickstart will try
                creating the <filename>kicktemp</filename> directory
                automatically. On most servers this works just fine.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <para>The third step is the Fine-Tuning of the extraction engine. You
        have to understand how it works first. Kickstart will start extracting
        files until the <guilabel>Maximum execution time</guilabel> threshold
        is reached. In fact, Kickstart allows for a 20% uncertainty of the
        accuracy of the elapsed time measurements, so the real duration may be
        somewhat less than that. If there are more files to extract, it will
        continue extraction in the next step. This approach allows it to work
        around the PHP time limit imposed by all hosts. However, if a step
        takes too little time, it is possible that your host mistakenly
        identifies this behaviour as a Denial of Service attack. As a result,
        Kickstart will force each step to last at least as much as the
        <guilabel>Minimum execution time</guilabel> value is. These two
        settings are expressed in seconds and can be perceived as a combined
        "from-to" step duration setting.</para>

        <para>Finally, you will find the options for the Stealth Mode in the
        Fine Tuning pane. The Stealth Mode allows you to display a static HTML
        page (optionally with images and SWF animation) to all visitors to the
        web site except yourself while you perform the restoration and only
        works with Apache or any other server supports mod_redirect
        functionality using .htaccess files (even some versions of IIS with
        third party add-ons do). This will prevent accidental disclosure of
        sensitive information while the restoration is in progress. This is
        performed by directing all traffic not coming from your IP address to
        the page you define in here. The first, obvious, setting is the
        <guilabel>Stealth mode</guilabel> check box. When you tick it, the
        stealth mode will be activated. The <guilabel>HTML file to show to web
        visitors</guilabel> option allows you to define the name of the static
        HTML page to show to your visitors. The file and its resources
        (images, CSS, Javascript files) must reside inside your to-be-restored
        site's root. You must only define the name of the file to use, not its
        URL. This means that <filename>offline.html</filename> is a valid
        setting, whereas <uri>http://www.example.com/offline.html</uri> is
        INVALID and will result in a 404 error thrown to your visitors.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>If you are worried about SEO, fear not. The redirection
          happens with a "temporary redirection" HTTP status code, which will
          instruct search engines to revisit your site in a later time. As a
          result, you are not penalized for duplicate content or otherwise
          negatively affect your SEO while restoring your site.</para>
        </tip>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>The extraction page</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.03.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>The fourth step is the fun part. Just click on the big, friendly
        <guibutton>Start</guibutton> button and sit back while Kickstart
        extracts your archive.</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>The restoration and clean up page, right after the
            extraction</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.04.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>When the extraction is complete, you will be presented with an
        option to launch the installer. Clicking on the large green button
        will launch the <uri>installation/index.php</uri> relative URL to a
        new window. If you were extracting a backup archive taken with Akeeba
        Backup, this will cause the Akeeba Backup Installer (ABI) which was
        included in your archive and just extracted to be launched.
        Technically, you will not be running Kickstart at that point, so you
        have to refer to the Akeeba Backup documentation for more information
        on how the restoration script works. <emphasis role="bold">Please do
        not close Kickstart's window</emphasis>. You will need it
        later.</para>

        <para>After you have completed your site's restoration and you close
        the installation script's window, you will get back to Kickstart. The
        interface has changed slightly in the meantime:</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>The restoration and clean up page, right after the
            restoration</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.05.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>Just click on the <guibutton>Clean Up</guibutton> button. The
        following actions will be performed:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The <filename>installation</filename> directory is removed
            as it is no longer required.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>If you had a <filename>.htaccess</filename> and/or
            <filename>php.ini</filename> files in your backed up site's root,
            these files have been extracted under the temporary names of
            <filename>htaccess.bak</filename> and
            <filename>php.ini.bak</filename> respectively. At this point, the
            temporary named files are renamed back to their original
            names.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The backup archive (and all its parts, if it is a multi-part
            archive) is removed.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><filename>kickstart.php</filename> itself and all of its
            translation INI files, if present, are removed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>The final page</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.06.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>At this point you can simply close Kickstart's window.
        Alternatively, you click on either button (or both!) to open the
        respective area of your site to a new browser window/tab.</para>

        <section xml:id="troubleshooting">
          <title>Troubleshooting</title>

          <para><emphasis role="bold">I am getting an AJAX
          error...</emphasis></para>

          <para><emphasis role="bold">Kickstart tells me that this is not a
          valid JPA archive?</emphasis></para>

          <para>First, ensure that you have downloaded and uploaded the backup
          archive using FTP in Binary transfer mode. If not, do it now. This
          is the mest common cause of issues. Then, make sure that you have
          tried both file writing modes (direct file writing and FTP mode) and
          neither works on your site. The next step would be lowering the
          <guilabel>Maximum execution time</guilabel> setting to 2 or 3
          seconds and setting the <guilabel>Minimum execution time</guilabel>
          to 1 second. If you are still getting this error message, please
          take a screenshot of the entire message (<emphasis>do not downscale
          it</emphasis>, we'll need to be able to read it) and post it in a
          post on our <link
          xlink:href="http://www.akeebabackup.com/forum.html">support
          forum</link>. Please include as much information as you can
          regarding the error condition, how you took your backup, which
          <emphasis>EXACT</emphasis> version of Akeeba Backup you were using
          ("latest" means nothing, something like 3.0.rc1 does), which EXACT
          version of Kickstart you were using and the PHP version of your
          host. Remember that the less information you give us, the more time
          it will take us to figure out what's going wrong and the less happy
          you'll feel about our support. We need you to help us help
          you.</para>

          <para><emphasis role="bold">I am getting "Can't open xyz for
          writing" or "Can't create directory xyz" error
          messages</emphasis></para>

          <para>The first thing you have to check, even though it sounds
          silly, is that you have enough free disk space. Most probably you
          have an account quota limit. Since you are extracting an archive,
          you must have at least as much as 2-3 times free space as your
          backup archive. This means that if you have a backup archive
          weighing 100Mb, you need another 150-200Mb to extract it. In total,
          you'd need 250-300Mb of free disk space before you begin uploading
          files and extracting the archive with Kickstart.</para>

          <important>
            <para>Some hosts claim "unlimited" disk space. Sadly, this is not
            always the case. Most hosts have "hidden" limits, such as the
            amount of files you can host under one account. If you go over
            that limit, you'll get extraction errors. Another thing is that
            you "unlimited" host is physically bound to the size of their hard
            drives. If their hard drive was close to completely filling up,
            trying to extract your site will also lead to a restoration
            failure. If nothing else helps with this kind of errors, do
            contact your host and ask them if you are hitting a file count
            limitation or their hard drive is full.</para>
          </important>

          <para>Moreover, some hosts have a limitation on the maximum file
          size PHP can create. For example, Strato allows PHP to create files
          of only up to 10Mb. Trying to extract bigger files from the archive
          will lead to such an error. Do note that you might be able to upload
          large files, such as your site's backup archive, through FTP.
          However, if you try to extract a large file from the archive (e.g. a
          large non-split database dump, a large video or music file, etc) it
          will fail. Your ONLY way to perform the restoration is to extract
          the archive on your local PC, e.g. using Akeeba eXtract, and
          uploading all the extracted files by FTP. All you'll have to do next
          is visiting the restoration URL which is in the form of
          <uri>http://www.yoursite.com/installation/index.php</uri>. Please
          refer to Akeeba Backup's documentation (the chapter on restoring
          your site) for more information.</para>

          <para>Finally, it may be a classic case of wrong or mixed file and
          directory permissions (a "permissions hell" situation). This is very
          easy to happen if you are restoring to a host with an existing
          installation of Joomla! which doesn't use suPHP, i.e. the majority
          of hosts. You might want to try using the FTP mode. If this still
          doesn't work for you, try removing all existing files and
          directories from your server before restoring the backup archive.
          It's very easy to mix up ownerships and permissions on a shared
          host, effectively entering into a "permissions hell" which is
          virtually impossible to work around unless you have root privileges
          on an SSH console or, more easily, removing all files from the
          account. Do note that removing files might require using both an FTP
          program and your host's control panel, or raising a ticket with your
          host.</para>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Advanced features</title>

    <section xml:id="profeatures">
      <title>Professional features</title>

      <para>As of version 3.5.0, there are two "flavours" of Akeeba Kickstart:
      the free of charge Akeeba Kickstart Core, available to all, and the
      for-a-fee Akeeba Kickstart Professional, available only to AKEEBAPRO and
      AKEEBADELUXE subscribers. The Professional flavour includes features not
      available in the Core version, designed to make a web professional's
      life much easier.</para>

      <section xml:id="import-url">
        <title>Import from a URL and quickly install a fresh copy of
        Joomla!</title>

        <note>
          <para>This feature is available in both Akeeba Kickstart Core (free
          for all) and Professional (subscribers only)</para>
        </note>

        <para>This feature allows you to import archives stored in any other
        web-accessible server. Please note that the file must be downloadable
        through the web without authentication, i.e. without needing to log in
        or provide a username, password or other means of authentication.
        Backup archives in the default backup directory of Akeeba Backup are,
        by default,<emphasis role="bold"> NOT</emphasis> web accessible for
        security reasons.</para>

        <para>This way you don't have to go through the extremely
        time-consuming steps of downloading files to your local PC and
        uploading them back to your new site, allowing for much faster site
        transfers between servers and/or site cloning. All you have to do is
        to use Akeeba Backup (Core or Professional) to backup your site, move
        the backup archive to a web-accessible location (e.g. your site's
        root), then use Akeeba Kickstart to restore the backup into any
        server, very easily.</para>

        <para>Moreover, this feature can be used to quickly install the latest
        version of Joomla!. Thanks to a special button (more below) it can
        automatically connect to the Joomla! official site, find out what is
        the latest version of Joomla! and put its URL in the download URL box.
        Since Joomla! installation packages use the same format and directory
        structure as Akeeba Backup ZIP archives Kickstart can "restore" them,
        allowing you to quickly install a fresh Joomla! site on any server,
        without time consuming downloads and uploads.</para>

        <important>
          <para>You ABSOLUTELY DO NOT need to install Joomla! before restoring
          a backup archive generated by Akeeba Backup. In fact, you are
          strongly advised to NOT install Joomla! AT ALL before restoring a
          backup archive generated by Akeeba Backup. Full site backups are
          restored best on an EMPTY hosting account.</para>
        </important>

        <para>In order to use this feature, upload Akeeba Kickstart Core or
        Professional into the root of the site where you want to restore your
        backup / install Joomla! and run it. Right under Step 1 you will see a
        small blue button reading <guibutton>Import from URL</guibutton>.
        Click on it. The following page appears:</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>Import from URL</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.12.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>If you are importing a backup archive from a web server enter
        its URL in the <guilabel>URL to Import</guilabel> field, then click on
        the <guibutton>Import from URL</guibutton> button.</para>

        <important>
          <para>If it is a multipart backup archive, i.e. a backup which
          consists of several files, you will need to repeat this for every
          archive part file.</para>
        </important>

        <para>If you want to install a brand new copy of
        <trademark>Joomla!</trademark> on your site first click on the
        <guilabel>Latest Joomla! Release</guilabel> button. Kickstart will
        connect to joomla.org, find the download URL of the latest version of
        Joomla! and fill in the <guilabel>URL to Import</guilabel> field
        automatically. This will take somewhere between 3 and 10 seconds. Once
        the <guilabel>URL to Import</guilabel> field is filled in just click
        on the <guibutton>Import from URL</guibutton> button.</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>Importing from URL</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.13.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>The download of the file begins. Depending on the capabilities
        of the server hosting your backup archive you will see a progress bar.
        If the remote server doesn't report the size of the backup archive,
        you will simply see the text below the empty bar indicating how much
        of the backup archive has already been imported.</para>

        <para>Once the import is complete you'll be presented with the final
        page of the importer:</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>Finished importing from URL</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.14.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>Click on the <guibutton>Reload Kickstart</guibutton> button to
        reload Kickstart and have it list your newly imported file.
        Congratulations! You are now ready to restore the backup archive you
        just imported / install Joomla!.</para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="pro-import-s3">
        <title>Import from Amazon S3</title>

        <note>
          <para>This feature is only available in Akeeba Kickstart
          Professional</para>
        </note>

        <para>This feature allows you to import archives directly from Amazon
        S3 into your site and let Kickstart extract them. This way you don't
        have to go through the extremely time-consuming steps of downloading
        files to your local PC and uploading them back to your new site,
        allowing for much faster site transfers between servers and/or site
        cloning. All you have to do is to use Akeeba Backup Professional to
        backup your site to Amazon S3, then use Akeeba Kickstart Professional
        to restore the backup into any server, very easily.</para>

        <important>
          <para>This feature will not work with buckets containing a dot in
          their name. This is a limitation on Amazon S3's side, namely the way
          their SSL certificates are set up.</para>
        </important>

        <para>In order to use this feature, upload Akeeba Kickstart
        Professional into the root of the site where you want to restore your
        backup and run it. Right under Step 1 you will see a small blue button
        reading <guibutton>Import from Amazon S3</guibutton>. Click on it. The
        following page appears:</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>Import from S3</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.08.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>Begin by entering your Amazon S3 Access Key and Secret Key in
        the two topmost fields and click on <guibutton>Connect to Amazon
        S3</guibutton>. If you change your mind, just click on
        <guibutton>Cancel Import</guibutton> to be transferred back to
        Kickstart's main page.</para>

        <para>A few seconds after pressing the <guibutton>Connect to Amazon
        S3</guibutton> button you will see the <guilabel>Bucket</guilabel>
        drop-down fill in with the names of the Amazon S3 buckets under your
        account. Select the bucket you want. If it is already selected, click
        on the <guibutton>List Contents</guibutton> button. A few seconds
        later, the third step's area will show you an explorer-style
        interface, listing the folders and files in your Amazon S3 account.
        Please note that only archive files (JPA, ZIP and JPS) are being
        listed in the files area.</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>Listing the S3 files and folders</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.09.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>You can navigate your directories by clicking on them. Once you
        find your backup archive, just click on it. Akeeba Kickstart
        Professional will begin importing it to your site. If it is a
        multi-part archive, Akeeba Kickstart Professional will automatically
        import all of the part files for you. You needn't worry about
        transferring each one of them separately!</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>Importing from S3</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.10.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>While the import is running it will show you the progress of the
        import process. Once it's done, you'll be presented with the final
        page of the importer:</para>

        <screenshot>
          <info>
            <title>Finished importing from S3</title>
          </info>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/kickstart.11.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>

        <para>Click on the <guibutton>Reload Kickstart</guibutton> button to
        reload Kickstart and have it list your newly imported file.
        Congratulations! You are now ready to restore the backup archive you
        just imported!</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="automating">
      <title>Automating Kickstart</title>

      <note>
        <para>This method is no longer supported and will be removed in an
        upcoming version of Kickstart.</para>
      </note>

      <para>Kickstart's automation is part of our 1-click site restoration
      initiative. The only prerequisite is that your backup archive must be
      created using the "Akeeba Backup Installer" (a.k.a. ABI) embedded
      restoration script. This is the default and only option, as of Akeeba
      Backup 3.0. However, the default option in newer versions of Akeeba
      Backup is ANGIE (Akeeba Next Generation Installation Engine) which is
      NOT compatible with this method.</para>

      <para>The automation procedure covers the entirety of the
      extraction/restoration process. Once you start Kickstart, it will
      extract the archive, call the ABI restoration script, it will
      automatically proceed through all of its pages and then allow you to
      click on the final Kickstart button which removes
      <filename>kickstart.php</filename>, the archive file and the
      installation directory.</para>

      <para>Everything is controlled by the contents of a single file which
      must be named <filename>abiautomation.ini</filename> and located in the
      same directory as <filename>kickstart.php</filename>. So, you only need
      to upload three files: <filename>kickstart.php</filename>, the archive
      and <filename>abiautomation.ini</filename>. If you do that, accessing
      kickstart.php from your browser will result in a fully restored site,
      without any user intervention (unless an error happens; in this case the
      process will halt for you to review and correct the error).</para>

      <para>The INI file is comprised of different sections. The section named
      <code>[kickstart]</code> is where all Kickstart-related parameters are
      stored.</para>

      <programlisting>[kickstart]
kickstart.setup.sourcefile=<replaceable>backupfile.jpa</replaceable>
kickstart.tuning.min_exec_time=1
kickstart.tuning.max_exec_time=5
kickstart.procengine=ftp
kickstart.ftp.host=<replaceable>ftp.example.com</replaceable>
kickstart.ftp.port=<replaceable>21</replaceable>
kickstart.ftp.ssl=0
kickstart.ftp.passive=1
kickstart.ftp.user=<replaceable>myuser</replaceable>
kickstart.ftp.pass=<replaceable>mypass</replaceable>
kickstart.ftp.dir=<replaceable>/public_html</replaceable>
kickstart.ftp.tempdir=/var/www/mysite/public_html/kicktemp</programlisting>

      <para>All those variables correspond to the options you are presented
      with when running Kickstart.</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.setup.sourcefile</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>REQUIRED. The name of the backup archive to extract. You can
            enter a relative or absolute pathname.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.tuning.min_exec_time</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The minimum time each extraction step may last, in seconds.
            Defaults to 1 second. It is advisable not to modify this
            parameter.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.tuning.max_exec_time</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The maximum time each extraction step may last, in seconds.
            Defaults to 5 seconds. If you are getting timeout errors or HTTP
            500 errors, you might want to lower this.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.procengine</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>How to write the extracted files to the disk. It can either
            be <option>direct</option> or <option>ftp</option>. In direct
            mode, all files are written using PHP file writing. In FTP mode,
            the files are first extracted to a temporary directory, then
            "uploaded" using FTP to their final location. The FTP mode is much
            slower, but it might be the only way for Kickstart to work on many
            servers.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.ftp.host</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>If you are using the FTP mode, this defines the address of
            the FTP server used for uploading the files. Do note that you must
            enter only the domain or IP address, without the protocol. This
            means that ftp.example.com is correct usage, while
            ftp://ftp.example.com is <emphasis>incorrect</emphasis>.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.ftp.port</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The TCP/IP port of the FTP server to use. Normally you want
            to use port 21 (default plain FTP port). Only use something
            different if your host tells you so, or if you are using FTPS (FTP
            over SSL).</para>

            <warning>
              <para>If your host tells you to use port 22, their connection
              mode is not compatible with Kickstart. Port 22 is used by the
              SFTP protocol, which is entirely different that the supported
              FTP and FTPS protocols. In this case you have to ask your host
              for plain FTP access to your site.</para>
            </warning>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.ftp.ssl</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Set it to 1 if you want to use the FTPS (FTP over SSL)
            protocol. The default value is 0 which means that Kickstart will
            use an unencrypted connection. Do note that Kickstart
            <emphasis>does not support</emphasis> SFTP, as it is an entirely
            different protocol than FTPS. The names look alike, but the
            protocols have nothing to do with each other.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.ftp.passive</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Set to 1 to use the FTP Passive mode (default), or use 0 to
            use the FTP Active mode. Most probably you want to use the default
            value of 1, as it is the only way to work around the firewall of
            your host. A very small minority of hosts require the Active mode,
            but they will tell you so in their FTP connection
            instructions.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.ftp.user</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The FTP username.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.ftp.pass</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The FTP password.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.ftp.dir</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>The <emphasis>absolute FTP path</emphasis> to your restored
            site's root. <emphasis role="bold">THIS IS NOT THE SAME AS THE
            FILE SYSTEM PATH TO YOUR SITE'S ROOT!!!</emphasis> The easiest way
            to figure this out is to use FileZilla. Connect to your target FTP
            server with FileZilla. Navigate to the web server's root (usually
            it's a subdirectory named httpdocs, htdocs, public_html, http_docs
            or www). Above the right-hand folder pane you will see a text box
            with a path. Copy this path and paste it to this setting.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>kickstart.ftp.tempdir</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>As PHP can't directly upload files while they are being
            extracted, Kickstart is extracting them to a temporary directory
            using direct file writes first, then uploads them to their final
            destination using FTP. Normally, Kickstart will try using the
            directory it's stored in to extract the temporary files. Many web
            hosts configure their servers in such a way that this is not
            possible. Using this option you can customise the location of the
            temporary directory to somewhere with adequate permissions. You
            can use either an absolute or a relative (to Kickstart's
            directory) path for this setting.</para>

            <para>If unsure, you can follow an easy workaround. Create a
            directory named <filename>kicktemp</filename> in your site's root
            using FTP and give it 0777 permissions (or world-write privileges,
            e.g. full control to the Everybody pseudo-user, if you are using a
            Windows server). Then type in <filename>kicktemp</filename> as
            this option.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para>Do note that defining Kickstart's parameters in
      <filename>abiautomation.ini</filename> is the first step to automating
      the restoration procedure. There are more sections for the
      <filename>abiautomation.ini</filename> file described in Akeeba Backup's
      documentation, under the "Automating the Akeeba Backup Installer"
      section.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <appendix version="5.0" xml:id="gnu-fdl">
    <title>GNU Free Documentation License</title>

    <para>Copyright (C) 2000, 2001, 2002 Free Software Foundation,
    <abbrev>Inc.</abbrev> 51 Franklin <abbrev>St</abbrev> , Fifth Floor,
    Boston, <abbrev>MA</abbrev> 02110-1301 <abbrev
    role="initialism">USA</abbrev> . Everyone is permitted to copy and
    distribute verbatim copies of this license document, but changing it is
    not allowed.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">0. PREAMBLE</bridgehead>

    <para>The purpose of this License is to make a manual, textbook, or other
    functional and useful document "free" in the sense of freedom: to assure
    everyone the effective freedom to copy and redistribute it, with or
    without modifying it, either commercially or noncommercially. Secondarily,
    this License preserves for the author and publisher a way to get credit
    for their work, while not being considered responsible for modifications
    made by others.</para>

    <para>This License is a kind of "copyleft", which means that derivative
    works of the document must themselves be free in the same sense. It
    complements the GNU General Public License, which is a copyleft license
    designed for free software.</para>

    <para>We have designed this License in order to use it for manuals for
    free software, because free software needs free documentation: a free
    program should come with manuals providing the same freedoms that the
    software does. But this License is not limited to software manuals; it can
    be used for any textual work, regardless of subject matter or whether it
    is published as a printed book. We recommend this License principally for
    works whose purpose is instruction or reference.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">1. APPLICABILITY AND DEFINITIONS</bridgehead>

    <para>This License applies to any manual or other work, in any medium,
    that contains a notice placed by the copyright holder saying it can be
    distributed under the terms of this License. Such a notice grants a
    world-wide, royalty-free license, unlimited in duration, to use that work
    under the conditions stated herein. The "Document", below, refers to any
    such manual or work. Any member of the public is a licensee, and is
    addressed as "you". You accept the license if you copy, modify or
    distribute the work in a way requiring permission under copyright
    law.</para>

    <para>A "Modified Version" of the Document means any work containing the
    Document or a portion of it, either copied verbatim, or with modifications
    and/or translated into another language.</para>

    <para>A "Secondary Section" is a named appendix or a front-matter section
    of the Document that deals exclusively with the relationship of the
    publishers or authors of the Document to the Document's overall subject
    (or to related matters) and contains nothing that could fall directly
    within that overall subject. (Thus, if the Document is in part a textbook
    of mathematics, a Secondary Section may not explain any mathematics.) The
    relationship could be a matter of historical connection with the subject
    or with related matters, or of legal, commercial, philosophical, ethical
    or political position regarding them.</para>

    <para>The "Invariant Sections" are certain Secondary Sections whose titles
    are designated, as being those of Invariant Sections, in the notice that
    says that the Document is released under this License. If a section does
    not fit the above definition of Secondary then it is not allowed to be
    designated as Invariant. The Document may contain zero Invariant Sections.
    If the Document does not identify any Invariant Sections then there are
    none.</para>

    <para>The "Cover Texts" are certain short passages of text that are
    listed, as Front-Cover Texts or Back-Cover Texts, in the notice that says
    that the Document is released under this License. A Front-Cover Text may
    be at most 5 words, and a Back-Cover Text may be at most 25 words.</para>

    <para>A "Transparent" copy of the Document means a machine-readable copy,
    represented in a format whose specification is available to the general
    public, that is suitable for revising the document straightforwardly with
    generic text editors or (for images composed of pixels) generic paint
    programs or (for drawings) some widely available drawing editor, and that
    is suitable for input to text formatters or for automatic translation to a
    variety of formats suitable for input to text formatters. A copy made in
    an otherwise Transparent file format whose markup, or absence of markup,
    has been arranged to thwart or discourage subsequent modification by
    readers is not Transparent. An image format is not Transparent if used for
    any substantial amount of text. A copy that is not "Transparent" is called
    "Opaque".</para>

    <para>Examples of suitable formats for Transparent copies include plain
    ASCII without markup, Texinfo input format, LaTeX input format, SGML or
    XML using a publicly available DTD, and standard-conforming simple HTML,
    PostScript or PDF designed for human modification. Examples of transparent
    image formats include PNG, XCF and JPG. Opaque formats include proprietary
    formats that can be read and edited only by proprietary word processors,
    SGML or XML for which the DTD and/or processing tools are not generally
    available, and the machine-generated HTML, PostScript or PDF produced by
    some word processors for output purposes only.</para>

    <para>The "Title Page" means, for a printed book, the title page itself,
    plus such following pages as are needed to hold, legibly, the material
    this License requires to appear in the title page. For works in formats
    which do not have any title page as such, "Title Page" means the text near
    the most prominent appearance of the work's title, preceding the beginning
    of the body of the text.</para>

    <para>A section "Entitled XYZ" means a named subunit of the Document whose
    title either is precisely XYZ or contains XYZ in parentheses following
    text that translates XYZ in another language. (Here XYZ stands for a
    specific section name mentioned below, such as "Acknowledgements",
    "Dedications", "Endorsements", or "History".) To "Preserve the Title" of
    such a section when you modify the Document means that it remains a
    section "Entitled XYZ" according to this definition.</para>

    <para>The Document may include Warranty Disclaimers next to the notice
    which states that this License applies to the Document. These Warranty
    Disclaimers are considered to be included by reference in this License,
    but only as regards disclaiming warranties: any other implication that
    these Warranty Disclaimers may have is void and has no effect on the
    meaning of this License.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">2. VERBATIM COPYING</bridgehead>

    <para>You may copy and distribute the Document in any medium, either
    commercially or noncommercially, provided that this License, the copyright
    notices, and the license notice saying this License applies to the
    Document are reproduced in all copies, and that you add no other
    conditions whatsoever to those of this License. You may not use technical
    measures to obstruct or control the reading or further copying of the
    copies you make or distribute. However, you may accept compensation in
    exchange for copies. If you distribute a large enough number of copies you
    must also follow the conditions in section 3.</para>

    <para>You may also lend copies, under the same conditions stated above,
    and you may publicly display copies.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">3. COPYING IN QUANTITY</bridgehead>

    <para>If you publish printed copies (or copies in media that commonly have
    printed covers) of the Document, numbering more than 100, and the
    Document's license notice requires Cover Texts, you must enclose the
    copies in covers that carry, clearly and legibly, all these Cover Texts:
    Front-Cover Texts on the front cover, and Back-Cover Texts on the back
    cover. Both covers must also clearly and legibly identify you as the
    publisher of these copies. The front cover must present the full title
    with all words of the title equally prominent and visible. You may add
    other material on the covers in addition. Copying with changes limited to
    the covers, as long as they preserve the title of the Document and satisfy
    these conditions, can be treated as verbatim copying in other
    respects.</para>

    <para>If the required texts for either cover are too voluminous to fit
    legibly, you should put the first ones listed (as many as fit reasonably)
    on the actual cover, and continue the rest onto adjacent pages.</para>

    <para>If you publish or distribute Opaque copies of the Document numbering
    more than 100, you must either include a machine-readable Transparent copy
    along with each Opaque copy, or state in or with each Opaque copy a
    computer-network location from which the general network-using public has
    access to download using public-standard network protocols a complete
    Transparent copy of the Document, free of added material. If you use the
    latter option, you must take reasonably prudent steps, when you begin
    distribution of Opaque copies in quantity, to ensure that this Transparent
    copy will remain thus accessible at the stated location until at least one
    year after the last time you distribute an Opaque copy (directly or
    through your agents or retailers) of that edition to the public.</para>

    <para>It is requested, but not required, that you contact the authors of
    the Document well before redistributing any large number of copies, to
    give them a chance to provide you with an updated version of the
    Document.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">4. MODIFICATIONS</bridgehead>

    <para>You may copy and distribute a Modified Version of the Document under
    the conditions of sections 2 and 3 above, provided that you release the
    Modified Version under precisely this License, with the Modified Version
    filling the role of the Document, thus licensing distribution and
    modification of the Modified Version to whoever possesses a copy of it. In
    addition, you must do these things in the Modified Version:</para>

    <orderedlist numeration="upperalpha">
      <listitem>
        <simpara>Use in the Title Page (and on the covers, if any) a title
        distinct from that of the Document, and from those of previous
        versions (which should, if there were any, be listed in the History
        section of the Document). You may use the same title as a previous
        version if the original publisher of that version gives
        permission.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>List on the Title Page, as authors, one or more persons or
        entities responsible for authorship of the modifications in the
        Modified Version, together with at least five of the principal authors
        of the Document (all of its principal authors, if it has fewer than
        five), unless they release you from this requirement.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>State on the Title page the name of the publisher of the
        Modified Version, as the publisher.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Preserve all the copyright notices of the Document.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Add an appropriate copyright notice for your modifications
        adjacent to the other copyright notices.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Include, immediately after the copyright notices, a license
        notice giving the public permission to use the Modified Version under
        the terms of this License, in the form shown in the Addendum
        below.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Preserve in that license notice the full lists of Invariant
        Sections and required Cover Texts given in the Document's license
        notice.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Include an unaltered copy of this License.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Preserve the section Entitled "History", Preserve its Title,
        and add to it an item stating at least the title, year, new authors,
        and publisher of the Modified Version as given on the Title Page. If
        there is no section Entitled "History" in the Document, create one
        stating the title, year, authors, and publisher of the Document as
        given on its Title Page, then add an item describing the Modified
        Version as stated in the previous sentence.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Preserve the network location, if any, given in the Document
        for public access to a Transparent copy of the Document, and likewise
        the network locations given in the Document for previous versions it
        was based on. These may be placed in the "History" section. You may
        omit a network location for a work that was published at least four
        years before the Document itself, or if the original publisher of the
        version it refers to gives permission.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>For any section Entitled "Acknowledgements" or "Dedications",
        Preserve the Title of the section, and preserve in the section all the
        substance and tone of each of the contributor acknowledgements and/or
        dedications given therein.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Preserve all the Invariant Sections of the Document,
        unaltered in their text and in their titles. Section numbers or the
        equivalent are not considered part of the section titles.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Delete any section Entitled "Endorsements". Such a section
        may not be included in the Modified Version.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Do not retitle any existing section to be Entitled
        "Endorsements" or to conflict in title with any Invariant
        Section.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <simpara>Preserve any Warranty Disclaimers.</simpara>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>If the Modified Version includes new front-matter sections or
    appendices that qualify as Secondary Sections and contain no material
    copied from the Document, you may at your option designate some or all of
    these sections as invariant. To do this, add their titles to the list of
    Invariant Sections in the Modified Version's license notice. These titles
    must be distinct from any other section titles.</para>

    <para>You may add a section Entitled "Endorsements", provided it contains
    nothing but endorsements of your Modified Version by various parties--for
    example, statements of peer review or that the text has been approved by
    an organization as the authoritative definition of a standard.</para>

    <para>You may add a passage of up to five words as a Front-Cover Text, and
    a passage of up to 25 words as a Back-Cover Text, to the end of the list
    of Cover Texts in the Modified Version. Only one passage of Front-Cover
    Text and one of Back-Cover Text may be added by (or through arrangements
    made by) any one entity. If the Document already includes a cover text for
    the same cover, previously added by you or by arrangement made by the same
    entity you are acting on behalf of, you may not add another; but you may
    replace the old one, on explicit permission from the previous publisher
    that added the old one.</para>

    <para>The author(s) and publisher(s) of the Document do not by this
    License give permission to use their names for publicity for or to assert
    or imply endorsement of any Modified Version.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">5. COMBINING DOCUMENTS</bridgehead>

    <para>You may combine the Document with other documents released under
    this License, under the terms defined in section 4 above for modified
    versions, provided that you include in the combination all of the
    Invariant Sections of all of the original documents, unmodified, and list
    them all as Invariant Sections of your combined work in its license
    notice, and that you preserve all their Warranty Disclaimers.</para>

    <para>The combined work need only contain one copy of this License, and
    multiple identical Invariant Sections may be replaced with a single copy.
    If there are multiple Invariant Sections with the same name but different
    contents, make the title of each such section unique by adding at the end
    of it, in parentheses, the name of the original author or publisher of
    that section if known, or else a unique number. Make the same adjustment
    to the section titles in the list of Invariant Sections in the license
    notice of the combined work.</para>

    <para>In the combination, you must combine any sections Entitled "History"
    in the various original documents, forming one section Entitled "History";
    likewise combine any sections Entitled "Acknowledgements", and any
    sections Entitled "Dedications". You must delete all sections Entitled
    "Endorsements".</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">6. COLLECTIONS OF DOCUMENTS</bridgehead>

    <para>You may make a collection consisting of the Document and other
    documents released under this License, and replace the individual copies
    of this License in the various documents with a single copy that is
    included in the collection, provided that you follow the rules of this
    License for verbatim copying of each of the documents in all other
    respects.</para>

    <para>You may extract a single document from such a collection, and
    distribute it individually under this License, provided you insert a copy
    of this License into the extracted document, and follow this License in
    all other respects regarding verbatim copying of that document.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">7. AGGREGATION WITH INDEPENDENT
    WORKS</bridgehead>

    <para>A compilation of the Document or its derivatives with other separate
    and independent documents or works, in or on a volume of a storage or
    distribution medium, is called an "aggregate" if the copyright resulting
    from the compilation is not used to limit the legal rights of the
    compilation's users beyond what the individual works permit. When the
    Document is included in an aggregate, this License does not apply to the
    other works in the aggregate which are not themselves derivative works of
    the Document.</para>

    <para>If the Cover Text requirement of section 3 is applicable to these
    copies of the Document, then if the Document is less than one half of the
    entire aggregate, the Document's Cover Texts may be placed on covers that
    bracket the Document within the aggregate, or the electronic equivalent of
    covers if the Document is in electronic form. Otherwise they must appear
    on printed covers that bracket the whole aggregate.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">8. TRANSLATION</bridgehead>

    <para>Translation is considered a kind of modification, so you may
    distribute translations of the Document under the terms of section 4.
    Replacing Invariant Sections with translations requires special permission
    from their copyright holders, but you may include translations of some or
    all Invariant Sections in addition to the original versions of these
    Invariant Sections. You may include a translation of this License, and all
    the license notices in the Document, and any Warranty Disclaimers,
    provided that you also include the original English version of this
    License and the original versions of those notices and disclaimers. In
    case of a disagreement between the translation and the original version of
    this License or a notice or disclaimer, the original version will
    prevail.</para>

    <para>If a section in the Document is Entitled "Acknowledgements",
    "Dedications", or "History", the requirement (section 4) to Preserve its
    Title (section 1) will typically require changing the actual title.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">9. TERMINATION</bridgehead>

    <para>You may not copy, modify, sublicense, or distribute the Document
    except as expressly provided for under this License. Any other attempt to
    copy, modify, sublicense or distribute the Document is void, and will
    automatically terminate your rights under this License. However, parties
    who have received copies, or rights, from you under this License will not
    have their licenses terminated so long as such parties remain in full
    compliance.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">10. FUTURE REVISIONS OF THIS
    LICENSE</bridgehead>

    <para>The Free Software Foundation may publish new, revised versions of
    the GNU Free Documentation License from time to time. Such new versions
    will be similar in spirit to the present version, but may differ in detail
    to address new problems or concerns. See <link
    xlink:href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/">
    http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/</link> .</para>

    <para>Each version of the License is given a distinguishing version
    number. If the Document specifies that a particular numbered version of
    this License "or any later version" applies to it, you have the option of
    following the terms and conditions either of that specified version or of
    any later version that has been published (not as a draft) by the Free
    Software Foundation. If the Document does not specify a version number of
    this License, you may choose any version ever published (not as a draft)
    by the Free Software Foundation.</para>

    <bridgehead renderas="sect1">ADDENDUM: How to use this License for your
    documents</bridgehead>

    <para>To use this License in a document you have written, include a copy
    of the License in the document and put the following copyright and license
    notices just after the title page:</para>

    <blockquote>
      <para>Copyright (C) YEAR YOUR NAME.</para>

      <para>Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
      document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version
      1.2 or any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with
      no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts. A
      copy of the license is included in the section entitled "GNU Free
      Documentation License".</para>
    </blockquote>

    <para>If you have Invariant Sections, Front-Cover Texts and Back-Cover
    Texts, replace the "with...Texts." line with this:</para>

    <blockquote>
      <para>with the Invariant Sections being LIST THEIR TITLES, with the
      Front-Cover Texts being LIST, and with the Back-Cover Texts being
      LIST.</para>
    </blockquote>

    <para>If you have Invariant Sections without Cover Texts, or some other
    combination of the three, merge those two alternatives to suit the
    situation.</para>

    <para>If your document contains nontrivial examples of program code, we
    recommend releasing these examples in parallel under your choice of free
    software license, such as the GNU General Public License, to permit their
    use in free software.</para>
  </appendix>
</book>
